Niek Mooij

Personal Information:

Telephone number: +316 45737565

Email: mooij.niek@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 9 October 1996

Citizenship: Dutch
Place of residency: Utrecht

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/niek-mooij



Personal Profile

I am a goal-oriented mathematician with a passion for innovative ideas and collaborative solutions. Through the use of mathematics I want to make the world a better place. I am interested in research that combines multiple branches of science to make new discoveries. Among others, I have an interest in the following subjects (in arbitrary order).

- Dynamical systems,
- Algorithm design,
- Real-life networks,
- Numerical methods.

Education

- 2019-2022: Studies for a Master of Science degree in Mathematics at Utrecht University. Thesis: Generating Maximal Independent Sets Using Lotka-Volterra Dynamics (link to file). Grade: 8.5/10. Under supervision of I. Kryven (Utrecht University). Graduation date: 1st of July 2022. One publication on new algorithms for maximal independent set computation is expected to appear.
- 2015-2019: Studies for a Bachelor of Science degree in Mathematics at Utrecht University. Thesis: Entropy and Option Pricing (<u>link to file</u>). Grade: 8.5/10. Under supervision of K. Dajani (Utrecht University).
- 2015-2019: Studies for a Bachelor of Science degree in Physics at Utrecht University.

Work Experience

- 2018-2021: Teaching assistant at Utrecht University.
- Jul. 2019 Sep. 2019: IT automatisation at InAdmin RiskCo Group.
- Apr. 2017 Jul. 2018: Tuition teacher for secondary school at Lyceo.

Teaching

I have done a lot of teaching next to my studies. Not only do I like the interaction with students, but it also forces one to extend their knowledge of the subject to a higher level. My responsibilities consist of helping the students with exercises during tutorials and grading exercises.

For the course *Methods and Models in Complex Systems* I have also been responsible for developing all the graded exercises and putting together the tutorial exercises.

I have been a teaching assistant at the Utrecht University mathematics/physics departments at the following bachelor courses.

- Methods and Models in Complex Systems (2021).
- Introduction to Stochastic Processes (2021).
- Methods and Models in Complex Systems (2020).
- Introduction to Financial Mathematics (2019).
- Introduction to Geometry (2019).
- Mathematical Techniques 2 (2019).
- Mathematical Techniques 1 (2018).
- Introduction to Financial Mathematics (2018).

Extracurricular Activities

- **Teaching assistent training.** Aside from teaching, I have followed a course called *Teaching Assistant Training*, which prepares one to give tutorials.
- μ -games (2021-2022). I am a member of the board of organizers of the μ -games. This is a competition in mathematical problem solving, organized by the Utrecht University mathematics department, and aimed at students from Utrecht University.
- PhysiCie (2015-2019). For the physics study association I have been involved in organising guest speaker presentations aimed at students at both the bachelor as well as the master level.

Presentations

- Utrecht University research group dr. Kryven (May 2022). Title: Stable Roommates Problem On Optimal Preference Matchings.
- Utrecht University Ecology research group (January 2022). Title: Bifurcations in Lotka-Volterra Systems.
- Utrecht University research group dr. Kryven (November 2021). Title: Lotka-Volterra for Maximum Independent Set Problem.

Programming Skills

- Python.
- Latex.
- Matlab.
- C#.
- C++.

Personal Activities

- Basketball. I play competitive basketball with games in the weekends.
- Reading. In my free time I like to read, especially novels.
- Making pasta. Since half a year I am trying to perfect my homemade ravioli.